<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>erik.wiffin</title>
    <link>https://erik.wiffin.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on erik.wiffin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Erik Wiffin 2020.
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erik.wiffin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Plans: A Reference</title>
      <link>https://erik.wiffin.com/posts/design-plans-a-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erik.wiffin.com/posts/design-plans-a-reference/</guid>
      <description>When confronted with a complicated task, the first response of any developer is to dive in and start coding. This is precisely the wrong thing to do. I might sound hyperbolic, but it’s true. Every single design plan I have ever seen has resulted in a better understanding of the problem, and more importantly, a better solution delivered faster.
What is a design plan? A design plan is a short document describing a proposed implementation of a new feature or refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story Points As Effort &#43; Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://erik.wiffin.com/posts/story-points-as-effort-&#43;-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erik.wiffin.com/posts/story-points-as-effort-&#43;-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>The only way to perfectly estimate how long a task will take, is to do the task and measure how long it took. In most situations where you’re endeavoring to produce an estimate, this is not a practical way of providing it. At the other end of the spectrum, you can pick a random number and base your timeline on that. While this is a quick and easy way of coming up with an estimate, it is rarely helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Manual - Professionalism Among Agency Developers</title>
      <link>https://erik.wiffin.com/posts/missing-manual-professionalism-among-agency-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 14:23:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erik.wiffin.com/posts/missing-manual-professionalism-among-agency-developers/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to be a professional software developer at an agency? If you’re familiar with some of the big names in books about software design - books like Design Patterns, Code Complete, Domain-Driven Design - you may have noticed that they all share a particular assumption: you are working at a product company, on a single codebase, and there is a good chance you will be working on that same codebase five years from now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>